

Emilio Ziniades

ECONOMICS GRADUATE AND SELF-TAUGHT PROGRAMMER



#### Address

Cape Town, South Africa

#### Website

https://emilio.co.za

#### Email Address

emilioziniades@protonmail.com

### **OVERVIEW**

I am a South African born in Johannesburg and living in Cape Town. After studying economics, politics and philosophy for four years at the University of Cape Town, I have worked as a freelancer, offering tutoring lessons for university and high school students in English, History, Mathematics and Economics. During this time, I have also taught myself how to program and build software. This has allowed me to expand my offering to include website development and cryptocurrency consulting. My main interests are data analysis and cryptocurrencies. I am interested in working in these fields, and would be willing to learn anything necessary to bootstrap my knowledge in the relevant domain. I am a motivated self-learner, who has a genuine curiousity and delight for puzzles and problems.

# CERTIFICATIONS

Complete Python Bootcamp: From zero to hero in Python Udemy

June 2020

Certificate available upon request. **Link to course** 

## **SKILLS**

Python	Stata
Intermediate	Intermediate
ReactJS	Go
Intermediate	Beginner
R & RStudio	Adobe Illustrato
Beginner	Beginner
Word, Excel and	Wordpress
Powerpoint	development
Competent	Competent

# LANGUAGES

<b>English</b>	<b>Afrikaans</b>
Native	Basic
<b>French</b>	<b>Greek</b>
Basic	Basic

## HOBBIES

Reading books, watching films

Five-a-side soccer, running and

yoga

Writing

Chess

**WORK EXPERIENCE** 

## Thirsty Fish

Owner

(December 2020 - Present)

Freelance technical consulting business, providing support for a variety of jobs including cryptocurrency technology consulting and website development. I have helped people set up hardware wallets and move their cryptocurrency off exchanges onto their wallets. I have assisted multiple people in Bitcoin recovery, when they have forgotten their passphrase or sent BTC to a LTC address.

## Monkey Films

Office Manager and Production Assistant

(January 2020 - April 2020)

Addressed various technical and administrative issues arising on film set and in the office, as well as assisting production both during shooting and in preproduction.

# Phaphama SEDI (Social Enterprise Development Initiative)

(February 2019 - November 2019)

Consultant

Consulted to All-in-One Online Shop, a small business based in Philippi which delivers groceries in Zimbabwe. Provided support regarding financial record-keeping, overall business strategy, online brand image and maintenance of customer relations.

# University of Cape Town

Teaching Assistant

(January 2018 - December 2019)

Taught and marked essays for a variety of undergraduate Philosophy and Economics courses (PHI1024F, PHI2037F, ECO2004S and ECO3025S). Responsibilities included teaching weekly classes as well as essay, test and exam marking.

## Emilio Tutors

Owner

(January 2016 - Present)

Freelance tutoring business. 1-on-1 and group tutoring lessons conducted for high school students in Maths, History and Science, and for undergraduate university students in Economics. In addition to teaching, I am responsible for all financial, administrative and IT-related roles. I built a Wordpress website (https://emiliotutors.co.za) to promote my service, and self-hosted it.

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Cape Town

(January 2019 - December 2019)

Bachelor of Commerce Honours in Economics

Degree GPA: 74.5%

Degree obtained in the second-class division one. Class medal obtained for Environmental Economics (ECO40525).

## University of Cape Town

(January 2016 -December 2018)

Bachelor of Social Sciences in Politics, Philosophy and Economics

Degree GPA: 79%

Degree obtained with distinction, and a distinction received in Economics. Placed on the Humanities Dean's List in all three years of study. Awarded 3 class medals for Introduction to Philosophy (PHI1024F), Introduction to Politics (POL1004F) and, Cooperation and Competition (ECO2007S).

## St John's College

(January 2011 - December 2015)

IEB Matric Certificate

Matric GPA: 91%

Matric obtained with 9 distinction. Top-acheiving student (highest overall average) for the class of 2015. Placed in the top 1 percent of IEB candidates for Maths, English, Science, History and Advanced Programme Maths.

## AWARDS

## Second Prefect

St John's College

October 2014

Deputy head-boy in matric year. Attended meetings with senior staff members. Co-ordinated a soup kitchen. Presented a student survey of the dining hall to the boarding committee.

## **Humanities Faculty Entrance Scholarship**

January 2016

University of Cape Town

Partial scholarship for academic fees.

# 3 x Humanities Dean's List (2016, 2017, 2018)

University of Cape Town

Award for academic excellence. Only awarded to top 20% of each faculty.

## Golden Key Society Member (2016-2019)

Golden Key Society

Consistently maintained GK membership across four consecutive years of study. Membership awarded to top 15 percent of each faculty every year.

## **REFERENCES**

anthony.black@uct.ac.za

Anthony Black	Anne Nettleton	Clare van Zyl
Professor, School of	Deputy Headmistress, St	Executive Producer,
Economics, University of	John's College	Monkey Films
Cape Town	+447341878206	+27828554314
021 650 2729	nettletonanne@gmail.com.clare@monkeyfilms.co.za	